i want to share with you four of the
newest javascript features that were
just released this month these features
are from the ecmascript 2022 or
es2022 standard which is the latest
javascript specification released first
we have the top level await before if we
wanted to use a weight we had to do it
inside of an async function that was the
rule with es2022 that rule is gone and
now we can use a weight in our modules
without having to use async functions so
instead of doing something like this
we can now just do something like this
it looks so much better now
next we have error costs with error
costs we can create better error
messages by explaining what the cause of
the error was before when creating an
error all we could do was write an error
message but now we can explain what
caused the error by doing something like
this the error code allows us to specify
exactly what went wrong but it also
makes it possible to reuse the same
error message but specify a different
cost and to access the cost of the error
just like we do ever that message we can
now do error that cost
next we have that at
that ad allows us to access any index of
an array now i know we could do this
before all we had to do was use the
square brackets but the difference
between square brackets and that ad is
that with that ad we can also search
backwards i can use that ad with -1 and
that will give me the last item it will
search backwards from the end to the
start of the array to finish up we have
class fields which makes javascript
finally feel like a grown-up
professional language to do
object-oriented programming with now
classes in javascript can have private
methods and properties which was
something that wasn't possible before
they can also have static methods and we
don't have to use constructor to
initialize properties which again was
something that wasn't possible before
now let's take a look at these features
one by one to make a private method or
property all we have to do is put the
hashtag sign before their name here we
have a private method
now if we try to call it as you can see
it won't work because it's private it is
the same with properties here we are
creating a message class with a private
text property and as you can also see we
are not using constructor at all before
we could not have created a private
property and we would have had to use
constructor to initialize a property as
you can see now the code looks so much
better
finally we can also create static
methods before we would have to do
something like this
now all we have to do is this and if we
want to we can make it private as well
these are not all the features from the
es2022 specification but these are the
ones that i wanted to share with you if
you like this content and you want to
support the channel and myself please
leave a like and subscribe just two
clicks is free for you but it helps me a
lot and what it's also for free are our
javascript react react native typescript
and graphql courses among many many
others so please if you want to become a
developer and you want to do it for free
with me please click the link below and
i will see you there stay healthy stay
happy eat kimchi kamzamita salad hey yo
see you on the next one bye